MAN: Previously on Gotham...
FALCONE: Jim, meet
my daughter, Sofia.
Do you ever think about
walking away from it all?
Sometimes.
BRUCE: This drawing depicts
a man being healed by water.
That's Ra's al Ghul.
He wants the knife.
AUCTIONEER: The opening
bid will begin at $50,000.
A hundred thousand dollars.
Two million dollars.
(GAVEL BANGING)
Sold to Mr. Bruce Wayne.
(EXHALES)
I guess you could say
I'm your number one fan?
What's black and
white and red all over?
Zebra, with a gaping hole.
I think something is
wrong with your brain, Ed.
ALVAREZ: Gordon,
you've got a visitor.
- You shouldn't have come back here.
- I'm a Falcone.
You came looking for a gangster.
That's exactly what you found.
(RA'S AL GHUL WHISPERING)
That knife is the key
to everything.
Well, not everything.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
NILES: Hmm.
Beautiful.
And you bought this at auction?
BRUCE: Supposedly, it
was the embalming knife
of the first-century
Mesopotamian king.
Balahsi.
And what is it that you
want of me, Mr. Wayne?
Anything you can
tell me, Dr. Winthrop.
I wanna know exactly
what it is I bought.
Perhaps you should've
considered that
before you dropped two million
dollars on it, shouldn't you?
Leave it with me overnight.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm back.
Man, you really need
to clean that room.
My delightful grandson.
I have access to the very clean
historical records room
at Gotham Central Library
and he uses it for his homework.
Oh, Alex, let me introduce you
to Mr. Bruce Wayne
and his guardian
- Alfred Pennyworth.
- What's up?
Whoa.
Where did that come from?
That cuneiform's
definitely pre-Phoenician.
Alex is an avid student of
history and sometimes assists me.
A word, Master Bruce.
Now it's all very well involving
an old geezer, but a young man?
Just you remember
who's after that knife.
What so important
about it that Ra's al Ghul
wants it so badly?
We need to know.
Dr. Winthrop.
Alex.
I have to ask you to keep
this matter between us.
- Of course.
- Yeah, cool.
I mean...
Yes, Mr. Wayne.
I'll check back tomorrow.
Until then.
No.
(GRUNTS)
Come on, Ed. Come on.
You can do this.
This has to be
the perfect riddle.
No!
(GROANS)
Yes.
Yes!
Is that you?
(SINISTER INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(GRUNTS)
Tomorrow night, Oswald,
is the night you die.
Alex.
Bring me the Palmerian Codex.
Ah!
What is it?
"He, who rises from the waters,
"whom death shall not touch.
"With this sacred blade,
"his final savage destiny
"shall be fulfilled.
"The earth will quake.
"Blood will flow.
"All tremble
"before the Demon's Head."
What's the Demon's Head?
Not what, my boy.
Who.
There is a legend in
the time of this knife,
of a man who could not die.
Or who died, but was reborn.
Have you ever, in your reading,
come across the name Ra's al Ghul?
He was a warlord.
But those guys always had
stories invented about them.
They're just stories.
My boy, people
believe in these stories.
They kill for them.
I think Bruce Wayne has
stumbled across something
much more complex
than he imagined.
And infinitely more dangerous.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
No one should be here.
Here, take this into my office.
Stay quiet. Quickly.
Dr. Niles Winthrop.
- What a pleasure.
- Who are you?
The museum is closed.
How did you get past the guard?
My apologies.
But my business is pressing.
"Greek, Vase - second Century."
Oh. (LAUGHS)
This was made by a forger in
Marrakech in the 15th century.
He had some talent, but
told the most obscene jokes.
Tell me who you are,
or I shall call the police.
I am looking for a knife Bruce
Wayne brought you earlier today.
I don't know what you mean.
The best liar I ever met
ran a brothel in Shanghai.
Her quite considerable
gift was that
you knew she was
lying, but didn't care.
You so badly
wanted to believe her.
(MAN SCOFFS)
You, Dr. Winthrop,
are a terrible liar.
Where's the knife?
(ALARM RINGING)
The police, they're coming.
I imagine they are.
(CHUCKLES)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
HARPER: End of crime, my ass.
Harper?
- Where's Bullock?
- He asked me to fill in.
He took a sabbatical
for a few days.
You baby-sitting me?
Do you need baby-sitting?
- What have we got?
- Dr. Niles Winthrop.
Curator of antiquities.
Looks like somebody
snapped his neck.
No witnesses, of course.
Fire alarm triggered security.
Maybe the dead guy
pulled it right before the...
Yeah, thanks. Anything else?
Yes, actually.
According to Professor
Von Dead's log book,
the last person to visit him,
I'm talking just
yesterday afternoon...
Bruce Wayne.
It's all right, let him in.
Detective Gordon.
What...
- What happened?
- We were thinking
we would ask you the same thing.
You met with Dr. Winthrop
just yesterday, correct?
I bought an old
knife at auction.
Dr. Winthrop agreed
to examine it for me.
I was coming by to
check on his progress.
When was he killed?
HARPER: According to the
fire alarm, just past midnight.
Whoever did it must
have snuck past security.
His grandson. Alex. He's
my age, a little bit younger.
- Have you talked to him?
- No one's seen any kid.
I'll get on it.
Where's the knife?
Alfred was right. I
shouldn't have left it.
Bruce, slow down.
What's this knife?
You think someone
would actually kill for it?
Detective Gordon, I'll tell
you what you want to know.
But all I ask is that
you let me come along.
If this is because of the
knife, then I'm responsible.
Bruce, a man is dead, a
child is potentially missing.
This is not time
to play detective.
What do you know? What's
so special about this knife?
As far as I know,
it's just an old knife.
But I paid a great deal for it.
And there was another
bidder. A very aggressive one.
Barbara Kean.
Right.
Well, Harper will track
down the grandson.
I'll deal with Barbara.
You go home.
I'll call you when I need you.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
You're here. Finally.
I've kept you
waiting. Apologies.
I see my guests have arrived.
Oh, yeah.
Gotta say, they don't do
much for the vibe of the place.
If you had acquired the
knife when I first requested it,
they wouldn't be necessary.
What's so special
about this knife anyway?
Sentimental value?
Only a destiny born
of blood and magic
two thousand
years in the making.
Uh-huh.
Now Dog-Boy here
is gonna fetch...
(SCREECHING)
His name is Anubis.
(LOW GROWLING)
And yes.
Bring me the knife.
And you can kill the boy.
(SCREECHING)
(OMINOUS INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
Boss.
Knocking, Victor.
We discussed this.
Uh-huh?
She's here.
Show her in.
Ms. Falcone, welcome to Gotham.
Mr. Cobblepot, it's a
pleasure to meet you.
Call me Oswald.
Please, have a seat.
Thank you for coming to see me.
I learned from my father
when the king of Gotham
summons you, you come.
And how is Carmine?
Can we hope to see
him sometime soon?
Shall we just address
the elephant in the room?
By all means.
My father's illegal businesses
hold no interest for me.
I'm here because the Falcone
family has a number of charities
that need my attention.
And you can only
provide that attention
by being here
personally. In my city.
- I understand your concern...
- Oh, do you?
(CHUCKLES)
But I assure you,
it's unfounded.
You know, your father
taught me many things.
Among them was to
nurture a healthy paranoia.
For example, when I took over,
some of his old capos
went underground.
Now, perhaps they've
vanished for good.
Or perhaps they're
waiting for a Falcone
to return to lead a rebellion.
(SCOFFS)
Who knows?
(LAUGHS MANIACALLY)
But, I hear your father's
voice whispering in my ear,
"Be careful."
Now...
I need to know that you
are not on some fool's errand
to rebuild your father's empire.
Otherwise...
I will stab you.
I was 13 when my
father first sent me away.
He said that Gotham
was too dangerous.
But this is my home.
I wanted to come home.
That's why I'm here.
Is that enough?
Gotham, Mother to us all.
I think we have
nothing to worry about.
Give your father
my best, will you?
("WHITE RABBIT" PLAYING)
(DOOR OPENING)
BARBARA: Jim.
What a lovely surprise.
Barbara.
Heard you popped up.
Seems like you landed
on your feet, as usual.
Hmm.
A woman has to stay busy.
You seem different.
You like this me better?
You recently bid
on a knife at auction.
(SCOFFS)
So much for catching up.
That knife is now missing and
the person who had it is dead.
What were you doing
last night around midnight?
I was here
with witnesses.
We done?
No.
This place.
The money you used
to bid on the knife.
- Who's bankrolling you?
- A client.
And, no, though tempting,
I can't give you the name.
BRUCE: Is it Ra's al Ghul?
If it is Ra's al Ghul, you don't
know who you're dealing with.
I don't know who or
what you're talking about.
Now, should I call my lawyer?
We'll be in touch.
Come here.
(MUSIC RISES IN TEMPO)
You followed me?
After I told you to stay away?
What the hell were you thinking?
I told you I'm responsible. You
should have let me come with you.
It's clear she's lying.
I can help you find
the killer, find Alex.
That's my job!
You wanna help?
Who is Ra's al Ghul?
And why didn't you
mention him before?
I wasn't certain
he was involved.
- The way she talked, I...
- You're lying, again.
Ra's al Ghul is the real
leader of The Court of Owls.
He's the one
responsible for the virus
and having me kidnapped.
(SIGHS IN DISBELIEF)
And you didn't think to
mention any of this before?
Why would he want the knife,
huh? What's so important about it?
I have no clue. That's what
I've been trying to find out.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Yeah?
- HARPER: Gordon, the kid's not at home.
Apparently, Grandad
was looking after him
while the parents
were traveling.
He's not at school,
no one's seen him.
Great.
Listen, I need all
the info you can get
on a man named Ra's al Ghul.
He could be connected.
Sure. But how do you spell...
No one's seen the boy.
He's either hiding
or the man who killed
his grandfather has him.
The police were triggered
by a fire alarm at the museum.
Alex could've pulled it,
taken the knife.
If so, he'd be hiding, scared.
Where could he be? Think.
I only met him for a second.
You want to play detective?
Now is your chance.
What was he wearing? What
did he say? Give me anything.
He had on his school uniform.
He just came from studying at...
Gotham Central Library.
His grandfather had a
room there. Alex has a key.
If he's hiding,
he's made a choice
not to trust the cops.
If I show up, he might run.
He needs to see a face
he knows. Come on.
Ed Nygma sent you?
The Edward Nygma?
(SCOFFS)
Do it again.
(BEAT-BOXING)
(SINGING) My once
friend Oswald, now my foe
It's me, Ed, just so you know
It's time we meet,
I think you'll agree
You'll find me where
the Earth meets the sky
Where water flows
and birds fly by
At dusk we'll meet,
I 'Il see you there
We'll settle things
unless you're scared
(EXHALES)
What the hell was that?
We should torture 'em.
Just get them to tell
us where Nygma is.
No, he just found
us on the street.
Well that's exactly
what you would say.
Leave!
That barmaid who kidnapped
Ed said he lost his step.
Clearly she was mistaken.
He's up to all of his old tricks.
So I'll meet him.
You and your men
will hide nearby.
Attack when I say.
Do not kill Ed though.
I want Victor to
freeze him again.
- Huh?
- Not you, the other Victor.
Oh.
"Earth meets sky,
"water flows, birds fly."
Obviously, he means the pier.
Gather your men.
I want Ed Nygma.
Historical Records room?
In the back.
(DOOR OPENS)
Alex?
It's me, Bruce Wayne.
You can come out, it's safe.
Alex, please, I just
wanna help you.
Alex.
This is Detective Gordon.
You can trust him.
Okay. Okay, all right.
I'm so sorry.
(STUTTERING) That
man, he killed him.
He killed my grandfather.
It was a man? You saw his face?
I only saw him from behind.
It was the knife. Did you
know it was dangerous?
No. I had no idea.
Alex, we need to get
you down to the station.
I can't. That man,
he'll think I saw him.
- He'll come after me.
- I will protect you, I promise.
He'll keep coming
till he gets the knife.
Alex, do you have
the knife with you?
No, I hid it.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
Take Alex and meet
me at the station. Go.
(SCREECHING)
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
Who sent you?
(SPEAKING ANCIENT LANGUAGE)
Thanks for clearing that up.
(BOTH GRUNTING AND GROANING)
(SCREECHING)
Bruce?
Run!
(BOOKSHELF CREAKING)
- Bruce Wayne call in?
- No.
We released a city-wide BOLO.
What about that name I gave you?
Zip. I tried Richard
Gull, Ralph Ghoul...
Detective Gordon?
Ra's al Ghul.
Minister of Antiquities attached
to the consulate of Nanda Parbat.
Thanks for coming in.
Nanda Parbat. That's
in the Himalayas, right?
Well done, Detective.
Few in your country have
even heard of our tiny nation.
Why don't we speak
in my captain's office.
A bit more private.
Of course.
- I'll be with you in a minute.
- Thank you.
I don't get it.
This is the guy that you're
looking at for murder?
Why does he just walk in?
Barbara must've told him
we were looking for him.
- Yeah, but...
- The two thugs at the library.
If they're working for him,
they would've told him
that we've contacted Alex.
He could think that
Alex gave us the knife.
I can use that.
Call Alfred Pennyworth.
See if he's heard
from Bruce Wayne.
That thing bit me.
- I need to get you to a hospital.
- No. No.
Then the police.
- Detective Gordon...
- No, I can't. I can't, they'll find me.
(SIGHS) I'm sorry.
I'm scared.
(SOBBING QUIETLY)
I don't know how you do it.
You fought those men, and I...
I just froze.
Same as when that
man killed my grandfather.
Fear is normal.
In the alley, when
my parents were killed
I was terrified.
I just stood there.
There's nothing
wrong with being afraid.
Once you realize it's normal
then you can put it in its place.
Then, you can act.
Fight back.
I felt bad for you.
When that happened
to your parents.
You were all the kids
at school talked about.
What did they say?
(EXHALES) That you
live alone in a mansion,
don't go to school,
fly around in jets.
They make you sound weird.
- Maybe I am.
- No.
You're cool.
I'm weird.
And you're a little
weird too, I guess.
But...
You're weirdly cool.
(SIGHS)
I'll take you to the knife.
Can I get you anything? Coffee?
That won't be necessary. I
think you know why I'm here.
- Enlighten me, Minister.
- Barbara Kean,
with whom you spoke, was
acting on behalf of my government
to procure a certain property.
Said property is the cultural
patrimony of my people.
Why not bid on
the knife yourself?
There were competing claims.
And if we bid officially,
alarms may have sound
and so it seemed
better to do it quietly.
But Miss Kean
failed.
And now,
regrettably, I understand
there's been a murder?
Dr. Niles Winthrop.
Curator at the Gotham
Natural History Museum.
That's awful.
But the reason
I'm here, Detective,
is to press my claim on
behalf of my government
and entreat you to
return the knife to me.
You say this knife is
important to your country.
Please explain.
(LIGHT CHUCKLE)
There is an ancient
story amongst my people
of a man who could not die.
In his time, he
committed terrible acts.
Raised a great kingdom.
And then vanished.
What happened to him?
If the legend is to be believed,
he walked away from his throne,
vowing that one day he would return
and complete his destiny,
but that would require
a particular knife.
This knife.
A story.
As I said.
But to my people,
very meaningful.
I hope that satisfies
your curiosity.
Some.
But you see, Minister,
my chief concern
is there's a boy, the
grandson of the curator.
He's being hunted.
Now, perhaps that's
because of the knife.
Or perhaps,
the killer thinks
he saw something.
Did he?
No.
- Then he's safe.
- Yes, but you see,
I would have to
know that for certain
before I would do anything
that might affect the case.
Such as release the knife.
May I see the knife, Detective?
It would so set my mind at ease.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Where the bloody hell is Gordon?
Gordon, incoming!
Gordon, where the hell is Bruce?
You!
- Alfred, back off!
- Wait, wait! Get your hands off me.
You don't know what
you've got in there.
I'm starting to, but
you are not helping.
I need you to calm down.
- Let me finish talking to him.
- Gordon.
- Not now!
- Gordon!
He's bloody vanished.
He knows we
don't have the knife.
We have to find Bruce.
- Donna Falcone.
- Do not call me that.
- You gotta hear us out.
- No, I don't.
I didn't invite you here.
We're not having this meeting.
Now I'm gonna ask you,
please, politely, to leave.
We served your father for years.
When Penguin took over,
we had to go underground.
Then we heard a Falcone
was back in Gotham,
we knew it was time.
Did you ignore my father
like you're ignoring me?
I just told you to leave.
Just tell us when your
father's coming back
to put that Penguin
in his place.
Please understand me,
my father is not coming back.
This is Penguin's city.
And I want you to leave
- before he finds out you're here...
- Too late, I'm afraid.
Victor, how many
graves did you dig?
Two.
But they're roomy.
(GUNSHOTS)
And there we are.
My paranoia is put to rest.
Phew! (SNIGGERING)
You used me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You had me come to your club.
You knew word would get out.
That my father's
loyalists would find me.
I was a worm on your hook.
With one difference, my dear.
The worm is usually eaten.
So you trust me now?
You're alive, aren't you?
I would plant roses.
They cover up the smell.
My father wouldn't
have killed those men.
He would've invited me to his club,
as you did, but then gone further.
He would've invited
me to dinners,
had us seen in public,
sent the message that
the old order supports me.
And those men you killed
would've pledged you loyalty.
Now they're fertilizer.
See, my father, he knew how
to build on the strength of others.
(SCOFFS)
But it's your city.
New times, new methods.
There was an ancient
Sumerian jewelry box here.
I just replaced it.
Hiding in plain sight.
Good thinking.
Bruce, there's a
legend about this knife.
(SIGHS) That terrible
things happen because of it.
But what if it's
not just a legend?
My grandfather is dead.
The man that killed him,
he can't have this.
I won't let him.
I promise.
(GLASS BREAKING)
We have to get out
of here. Run, run!
(SNIFFING AND SCREECHING)
(SNIFFING FRANTICALLY)
The Nanda Parbat consulate
is giving us the run around
and we can't get in
there without a warrant.
- Bruce still hasn't called you?
- No.
What the bloody hell were
you doing letting him tag along
with some murder investigation
in the first place, eh?
No, you do not get to lecture me
about a lack of honesty and openness.
You and Bruce have been
up to something for weeks.
What have you two
gotten yourselves into?
Damn it, Alfred.
I'm on your side.
Well, that may be, mate.
But whatever Master Bruce
decides to tell you is his decision.
Isn't it?
You are his guardian.
You are allowed
to violate his privacy
if it is gonna keep
him out of danger.
Stick to the point.
What are you doing
to find my boy?
What can I do, huh?
I have every cop
in this city on alert.
But as long as Ra's al
Ghul thinks he has that knife,
his life is in danger.
Yeah, right, and what
about the other boy?
Did he tell you where
he put the knife?
No. But I have to assume
Bruce is taking him to get it.
All right.
There's gotta be a clue
or something inside here.
- What?
- You stay here.
What?
The access I gave
you depended on trust.
If you can't be honest with
me, there's nothing I can do.
Harper.
If Mr. Pennyworth
tries to leave, arrest him.
On what charge?
She'll think of something.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(GASPING AND SCREECHING)
(SNIFFING)
I went to the pier.
I waited. Ed didn't show.
He...
- God, just get on with it!
- Right.
One, two...
(SINGING) I waited and
waited but you never came
You must be a coward
or worse, a lamebrain
I 'Il give you one
chance to make it right
Meet me again,
this time at midnight
I 'Il make this one easy
This place makes some people lie
Some people speak
and some people cry
Honestly, that
could be anything.
Can we please just
torture them, now?
Why not?
Wait a minute.
(EXHALES)
(SCREECHING)
Run.
Bruce.
Down!
(BRUCE GASPING)
Let's go. Let's go.
Take him, take him, go.
Get off of me.
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHING)
It's time you tell
me what's going on.
What is so important
about this knife?
Why are people dying for it?
Excellent question, Detective.
And you shall have
your answer soon.
Just give me the knife
and I will release the boy.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
(SOBBING)
Of course.
Bruce, hand me the knife.
Bruce. Hand me the knife.
You don't understand.
He killed Alfred.
And then brought
him back to life.
And Alex's grandfather
was afraid of this knife.
I can't give it to him.
If we don't hand it
over now, Alex is dead.
- That is all that matters.
- No.
You don't know who he is.
I can't.
Well done, Bruce.
You're finally beginning
to see things clearly.
The question is...
(KNIFE SLICING)
Are you strong enough?
(SCREAMS)
- No.
- Drop the weapon.
Hands in the air, on your knees.
Arrest me.
Ra's al Ghul is on
his way to Blackgate.
And we made contact
with Alex's parents.
It's gonna take them a
couple days to get home.
Bruce.
Ra's is a psychopath.
You're not responsible
for his actions.
I wanna help.
But everything
you've said so far,
Alfred dying and coming
back to life, magical waters.
Give me something I can believe.
Perhaps now you
understand why we held back.
It doesn't matter what
you say, Detective.
This is all my fault.
Alex is dead because of me.
I killed him.
Oswald!
I waited for you.
Again.
And you didn't show. Again.
You coward.
Where are you?
Here.
And I may be many things,
but I'm not a coward.
Your riddles suck.
"This place may
make some people lie,
"some people speak,
and some people cry."
That could mean anything.
Lying, speaking, crying.
You're just describing a
range of human behavior.
No!
I meant, lying, as
in "lying dead..."
Laying down. Lying down.
As in dead.
Oh.
The answer was Stoker
Cemetery. Clearly.
Only an idiot wouldn't see that.
Face it, Ed. You can't make
riddles to save your ass anymore.
I guess she was right.
- What? Who was right?
- Your number one fan.
She said that there was
something wrong with you.
Took me a while
to believe it, but...
(CHUCKLING)
You're not smart.
(LAUGHS)
I am too smart.
- I'm the Riddler.
- Oh, God, that name again?
Tell me, how long did it take
you to come up with those riddles?
- I don't know.
- A minute? Two minutes?
A few hours.
Six hours.
- Six hours?
- Yes!
For two bad riddles?
Does that sound
anything like the old you?
Well, perhaps I'm still recovering
from being frozen in a block of ice!
But revenge will certainly
make me feel better.
You will never
have revenge on me.
Ah! Yeah, I will.
- No, you won't.
- Oswald.
I'm gonna shoot you.
Yes. You might
shoot me, kill me,
but only he can
get revenge on me.
The man I froze on that pier.
The man who would've killed himself
before writing those idiotic riddles.
The man whose name
I still will not speak.
But he's gone.
(EXHALES)
You're just Ed Nygma.
And, not even Ed Nygma,
because Ed Nygma
would've noticed something.
What?
Doesn't it feel kind
of chilly in here?
(GROANS)
You remember him?
My other Victor?
I'm going to put
you on ice, again.
You want the same
pose or something else?
No, wait, please.
- Got it, same pose.
- No!
Okay, Oswald.
I'm not the Riddler.
Do it.
Stop.
I've changed my mind.
I'm not gonna freeze you.
I would only be
freezing Ed Nygma.
Who cares about that?
No. A better revenge
is having you live,
knowing that you're not him
and you never will be again.
Goodbye, Ed.
Who am I?
I must have been seven or eight.
It was late.
I snuck downstairs
to find my father
with a man before
him on his knees.
Begging for forgiveness.
My father stabbed
him in the neck.
The next morning, there
wasn't a trace of blood.
And we had
breakfast at that table.
Now you'd think I'd want to
stay far away from Gotham
but this house, this
city, is in my veins.
I'm home, Jim.
Word on the street is three
Falcone capos have gone missing.
They were in hiding.
Penguin used me as
bait to draw them out.
And killed them.
And you let him?
Don't act the innocent, Jim.
You came to Carmine
Falcone for help.
It was never going
to be bloodless.
So is that your plan?
Get close to Penguin, gain
his confidence, what then?
I need to know what
you're going to do.
No, you don't.
You want this city
back from Penguin.
I'll give that to you.
But you have to trust me.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENTS ON PA)
(ELECTRIC GATES BUZZING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(SINISTER INSTRUMENTAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
English - SDH